Mr. Wang hasn't finished the arrest,
السيد وانغ لم ينته من الاعتقال ،
so we have to ask the coroners to do autopsy.
لذلك علينا أن نطلب من المحققين إجراء تشريح للجثة.
I came late.
جئت في وقت متأخر.
How could it be such coincident?
كيف يمكن أن تكون هذه مصادفة؟
The content of the scroll repaired by the Fengs before their death
تم إصلاح محتوى اللفيفة من قبل Fengs قبل وفاتهم
turns out to be the legend of the Six Sages.
تبين أنها أسطورة الحكماء الستة.
I think the murderer did it on purpose.
أعتقد أن القاتل فعل ذلك عن قصد.
He seemed
بدا
to hide the red poison
لإخفاء السم الأحمر
into the pigments.
في الأصباغ.
There are only three headless and armless corpses.
لا يوجد سوى ثلاث جثث مقطوعة الرأس وبلا ذراعين.
Why do there lack three heads,
لماذا لا يوجد ثلاثة رؤوس ،
six arms,
ستة أذرع
and a complete corpse?
وجثة كاملة؟
One body has four heads and eight arms.
جسم واحد له أربعة رؤوس وثمانية أذرع.
The limbs that were lost at the scene
الأطراف التي فقدت في مكان الحادث
could be pieced together into the image of Morengen.
يمكن تجميعها معًا في صورة Morengen.
When Mr. Sun was poisoned,
عندما تسمم السيد صن ،
he was checking the seeds of herbs,
كان يفحص بذور الأعشاب ،
and his body
وجسده
was fixed into this posture.
تم إصلاحه في هذا الموقف.
Chu Qi'er was also fixed into the posture
تم تثبيت Chu Qi'er أيضًا في الموقف
of dancing when she was poisoned.
من الرقص عندما تسمم.
Did the murderer poison and fix the victims
هل القاتل سمم وأصلح الضحايا
to use their corpses to create
لاستخدام جثثهم لخلق
the images of Six Sages?
صور الحكماء الستة؟
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
the murderer also needed the corpses of
القاتل أيضا بحاجة إلى جثث
Mr. Sun and Chu Qi'er.
السيد صن وتشو كيير.
I've never heard someone
لم أسمع أحدا من قبل
would use humans to create statues.
سيستخدم البشر لإنشاء التماثيل.
Then why were the gavel
فلماذا المطرقة
and silk
والحرير
put here?
ضع هنا؟
Maybe they were the clues to the rest two victims' identities,
ربما كانوا مفاتيح هويات الضحيتين الباقيتين ،
and the murderer left them deliberately.
وتركهم القاتل عمدا.
=A League of Nobleman=
= عصبة النبلاء =
=Episode 8=
= الحلقة 8 =
Sir,
سيد،
the autopsy was done.
تم تشريح الجثة.
the three victims' death states were the same as Miss Chu's.
كانت حالات وفاة الضحايا الثلاثة هي نفسها حالات وفاة السيدة تشو.
They were killed by the same poison.
لقد قتلوا بنفس السم.
Then why did the three corpses
ثم لماذا فعلت الجثث الثلاث
bleed a little?
ينزف قليلا؟
They had been bled out
لقد نزفوا
before their heads
أمام رؤوسهم
and arms were cut.
وقطعوا ذراعيهم.
Then where was their blood?
ثم أين كانت دمائهم؟
No blood was left in the pavilion.
لم يترك دماء في الجناح.
Besides, there was another problem.
علاوة على ذلك ، كانت هناك مشكلة أخرى.
All the three corpses
جميع الجثث الثلاث
were bitten by fleas.
لدغات البراغيث.
Fleas?
البراغيث؟
The Feng family is reputable,
تتمتع عائلة فنغ بسمعة طيبة ،
and the Wuming Pavilion is also clean,
و Wuming Pavilion نظيف أيضًا ،
so how could there be fleas?
فكيف يمكن أن يكون هناك براغيث؟
Fleas like shady and damp places,
تحب البراغيث الأماكن المظللة والرطبة ،
so they couldn't appear here groundlessly.
لذلك لا يمكن أن يظهروا هنا بلا أساس.
The Wuming Pavilion is guarded heavily,
جناح Wuming خاضع لحراسة مشددة ،
and the four gentlemen from the Feng family
والأربعة السادة من عائلة فنغ
had been drawing here without leaving,
كان يرسم هنا دون أن يغادر ،
so how did the murderer
فكيف فعل القاتل
manage to enter here and poison them?
تمكنت من الدخول هنا وتسممهم؟
How did he remove
كيف أزال
the corpses and limbs?
الجثث والأطراف؟
I think there are other channels.
أعتقد أن هناك قنوات أخرى.
What sound is it?
ما هو الصوت؟
The smell of blood is so strong.
رائحة الدم قوية جدا.
The murderer actually dug a secret channel behind the cabinet.
لقد حفر القاتل بالفعل قناة سرية خلف الخزانة.
Inform Mr. Wang right now.
أبلغ السيد وانغ الآن.
Yes.
نعم.
The murderer actually dug through a secret canal.
لقد حفر القاتل بالفعل من خلال قناة سرية.
It's a secret canal again.
إنها قناة سرية مرة أخرى.
It seems the murderer
يبدو القاتل
acts through secret canals.
يعمل من خلال القنوات السرية.
I think he is not far away from us.
أعتقد أنه ليس ببعيد عنا.
There are traces of dragging.
هناك آثار جر.
The sound just now seemed
بدا الصوت للتو
to be made by dragging heavy things.
يتم صنعه عن طريق جر الأشياء الثقيلة.
He went to the left.
ذهب إلى اليسار.
The flow washed the traces away.
جرف التدفق الآثار بعيدًا.
There is another fork ahead.
هناك مفترق آخر أمامنا.
I don't know
لا أعرف
which direction we should choose.
أي اتجاه يجب أن نختار.
Close the sluice.
أغلق السد.
When the water ebbs,
عندما ينحسر الماء ،
the murderer's footprints
آثار أقدام القاتل
will be shown.
سوف تعرض.
Xu Dong,
شو دونغ
we'll chase after the murderer ahead,
سنطارد القاتل في المستقبل ،
and you go to close the sluice.
وتذهب لإغلاق السد.
Sir,
سيد،
be careful.
كن حذرا.
I'll be back soon.
سأعود قريبا.
The water level falls.
ينخفض ​​مستوى الماء.
His traces will be shown.
سوف تظهر آثاره.
Shush.
اسكت.
Go.
اذهب.
The corpses' limbs
أطراف الجثث
are all here.
كلها هنا.
I'm sure the murderer isn't far away from us.
أنا متأكد من أن القاتل ليس بعيدًا عنا.
There is a hole.
هناك فجوة.
Let's enter and check.
دعنا ندخل ونتحقق.
What place is it?
ما هو المكان؟
It seems like a prison.
يبدو وكأنه سجن.
It's a medicine jar.
إنها جرة دواء.
The patients were prisoned here.
تم سجن المرضى هنا.
It's not a prescription of medicine
إنها ليست وصفة طبية
but poision.
لكن السم.
What sound is it?
ما هو الصوت؟
It's the Shocking Thunder Bomb.
إنها قنبلة الرعد الصادمة.
Zhang Ping.
تشانغ بينغ.
It's not safe here.
الوضع ليس آمنًا هنا.
Get up now.
انهض الآن.
We're stuck.
كنا عالقين.
Stop trying.
توقف عن المحاولة.
Who is it?
من هذا؟
I'm a ghost,
انا شبح،
hiding in secret canals all the time.
يختبئون في قنوات سرية طوال الوقت.
Stop mystifying deliberately.
توقف عن الغموض عمدا.
Who are you?
من أنت؟
Look at the intelaced channels.
انظر إلى القنوات الذكية.
Don't they look like the network of Capital City?
ألا تبدو مثل شبكة العاصمة؟
If we regard Capital City as a human,
إذا اعتبرنا العاصمة كإنسان ،
this place
هذا المكان
is a tumor in his veins.
هو ورم في عروقه.
What have you done here?
ماذا فعلت هنا؟
Everyone that came here
كل من جاء إلى هنا
experienced the pain of poison eroding their bones
عانوا من آلام السموم التي أدت إلى تآكل عظامهم
and died.
و مات.
You killed them.
قتلتهم.
You're ignorant.
أنت جاهل.
Everyone will experience life and death.
كل شخص سيختبر الحياة والموت.
Only when they experience death
فقط عندما يختبرون الموت
will they know what life means.
هل سيعرفون ما تعنيه الحياة.
Why did you kill Mr. Sun
لماذا قتلت السيد صن
and Chu Qi'er?
و Chu Qi'er؟
You're smart,
انت ذكي،
so why don't you deduce?
فلماذا لا تستنتج؟
Where is Gong Yuzhen?
أين هو غونغ يوزين؟
What did you do to her?
ماذا فعلت لها؟
She's my Musician-sage,
إنها الموسيقي الحكيم الخاص بي ،
Ronakin.
رونكين.
It's not time for her to die.
لم يحن وقت موتها.
Don't you hurt her.
لا تؤذيها.
Do you know why
هل تعرف لماذا
it is covert here?
إنه مخفي هنا؟
It's because everyone that comes here
هذا لأن كل من يأتي إلى هنا
is doomed to die.
محكوم عليه بالموت.
People inside
الناس في الداخل
could leave
يمكنك الرحيل
only when they die.
فقط عندما يموتون.
You're hurt.
أنت مجروح.
It's shady and dirty here,
المكان مظلل وقذر هنا ،
so you're easy to get infected.
لذلك من السهل أن تصاب بالعدوى.
You'd better wrap it up now.
من الأفضل أن تختتمها الآن.
Zhang Ping,
تشانغ بينغ ،
I know you're still mad at me,
أعلم أنك ما زلت غاضبًا مني ،
but we're trapped here,
لكننا محاصرون هنا ،
and I don't know if we'll be alive or not.
ولا أعرف ما إذا كنا سنعيش أم لا.
I'm willing to work together with you
أنا على استعداد للعمل معك
and...
و...
I have an idea.
لدي فكرة.
The murderer killed people
قتل القاتل الناس
according to the chronological order of the Six Sages' births.
حسب الترتيب الزمني لولادات الحكماء الستة.
The Musician-sage was born the last.
ولد الموسيقار حكيم آخر.
That's why the murderer said
لهذا قال القاتل
it was not time for Miss Gong to die.
لم يحن الوقت لموت الآنسة غونغ.
As long as we find the rest two people
طالما وجدنا الباقي شخصين
before he kills her,
قبل أن يقتلها ،
we'll have a chance to stop him.
لدينا فرصة لإيقافه.
You're casting pearls before swine.
أنت تصب اللآلئ قبل الخنازير.
I was thinking about the case just now,
كنت أفكر في القضية الآن ،
but I heard your words,
لكني سمعت كلامك
Mr. Lan.
السيد.  لان.
You saved me,
قمت بحفظه لي،
so I should thank you.
لذا يجب أن أشكرك.
Thank you, Mr. Lan.
شكرا لك سيد لان.
However, you indeed did it wrongly
ومع ذلك ، لقد فعلت ذلك بشكل خاطئ بالفعل
on Miss Gong's matter.
بشأن مسألة الآنسة غونغ.
No matter what reason you have,
بغض النظر عن السبب لديك ،
- you can't deny the fact. - You can't deny the fact.
- لا يمكنك إنكار الحقيقة.  - لا يمكنك إنكار الحقيقة.
How priceless
كيف لا تقدر بثمن
your loyalty is.
ولاءك.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
you said
أنت قلت
there were rest two people.
كان هناك راحة شخصين.
Who are they?
من هؤلاء؟
I don't know.
لا أعلم.
Judging from the standard the murderer used to choose victims,
انطلاقا من المعيار الذي استخدمه القاتل لاختيار الضحايا ،
I think the rest two people
أعتقد أن الباقي شخصان
are the top in their respective fields.
هم الأفضل في مجالات تخصصهم.
Wait.
انتظر.
Do you remember the silk on the scroll of the Six Sages?
هل تتذكر الحرير على لفائف الحكماء الستة؟
I didn't have time to ponder about it by then,
لم يكن لدي وقت للتفكير في الأمر بحلول ذلك الوقت ،
but now I remember
لكنني الآن أتذكر
that is the Red Gilding Silk
هذا هو حرير التذهيب الأحمر
from Yunshang Community.
من مجتمع Yunshang.
The silk is woven by gold foil and silk yarns,
الحرير منسوج بورق الذهب وخيوط الحرير ،
and it's classified as a tribute.
وتصنف على أنها تحية.
Only Miss Wu from Yunshang Coummity can weave it.
فقط ملكة جمال وو من Yunshang Coummity يمكنها نسجها.
If so,
لو ذلك،
she is most likely to be chosen by the murderer
من المرجح أن يختارها القاتل
to be the Farmer and Sericulturist Sage, Zansang.
ليكون المزارع وصانع دودة القز Sage ، Zansang.
How about the gavel?
ماذا عن المطرقة؟
There is a mark of the Court of Judicial Review on it.
عليها علامة محكمة المراجعة القضائية.
The Warden-sage, Uyu,
The Warden-sage ، Uyu ،
is Mr. Tao, the judge of the Court of Judicial Review.
هو السيد تاو ، قاضي محكمة المراجعة القضائية.
Oh, no.
أوه لا.
He's going to kill the two of them.
سوف يقتل الاثنين.
We have to leave as soon as possible.
علينا المغادرة في أسرع وقت ممكن.
The more we delay,
كلما تأخرنا ،
the more dangers they are in.
كلما زادت الأخطار التي يتعرضون لها.
I don't know when Xu Dong and Mowen
لا أعرف متى شو دونغ وموين
will find us.
سوف تجدنا.
Don't you feel strange?
ألا تشعر بالغرابة؟
The murderer has been usually leaving clues
عادة ما يترك القاتل أدلة
since his first murder.
منذ مقتله الأول.
He seems to play games with us.
يبدو أنه يلعب معنا.
Perhaps he left a riddle
ربما ترك لغزا
in his
في
mysterious words.
كلمات غامضة.
Everyone will experience life and death.
كل شخص سيختبر الحياة والموت.
Only when they experience death
فقط عندما يختبرون الموت
will they know what life means.
هل سيعرفون ما تعنيه الحياة.
Does he mean
هل يقصد
everything mutually reinforces,
كل شيء يعزز بشكل متبادل ،
neutralizes, and depends on each other?
تحيد ، وتعتمد على بعضها البعض؟
Since the entrance is the life gate,
بما أن المدخل هو بوابة الحياة ،
there must be the death gate.
يجب أن يكون هناك بوابة الموت.
People will die
سيموت الناس
after entering from outside.
بعد الدخول من الخارج.
People inside can leave alive
يمكن للناس في الداخل أن يغادروا أحياء
only when they die.
فقط عندما يموتون.
This is the incinerator.
هذه هي المحرقة.
It is the death gate.
إنها بوابة الموت.
Mr. Lan,
السيد.  لان ،
the chimney is the exit.
المدخنة هي المخرج.
Is anyone here?
هل يوجد احد هنا
Please.
لو سمحت.
Save us.
أنقذنا.
We are here.
نحن هنا.
It's Zhang Ping.
إنه تشانغ بينغ.
Where are you?
أين أنت؟
It's Xu Dong.
إنه شو دونغ.
Sir.
سيد.
Zhang Ping.
تشانغ بينغ.
They are underneath.
هم تحتها.
Come on.
تعال.
Remove them.
احذفهم.
Sir.
سيد.
Peizhi.
Peizhi.
Are you okay?
هل انت بخير؟
Never mind.
لا تهتم.
Miss Wu and Mr. Tao are in danger.
الآنسة وو والسيد تاو في خطر.
We're pressed for time.
نحن مضغوطون للوقت.
Let's split out.
دعونا نفترق.
I'll go to save Miss Wu.
سأذهب لإنقاذ الآنسة وو.
Okay.
تمام.
I'll go to save Mr. Tao.
سأذهب لإنقاذ السيد تاو.
Go.
اذهب.
(Court of Judicial Review)
(محكمة المراجعة القضائية)
A momentary slip
زلة مؤقتة
will make us feel
سوف تجعلنا نشعر
everything we've done is wrong.
كل ما فعلناه خاطئ.
A momentary slip will make us feel everything we've done is wrong.
سيجعلنا الانزلاق اللحظي نشعر بأن كل ما فعلناه خطأ.
Only when I think everything twice before doing it will I feel no regret.
فقط عندما أفكر في كل شيء مرتين قبل القيام بذلك لن أشعر بأي ندم.
(Brochure of the Persuasion for Goodness) Only when I think everything twice before doing it will I feel no regret.
(كتيب الإقناع من أجل الخير) فقط عندما أفكر في كل شيء مرتين قبل القيام بذلك ، لن أشعر بأي ندم.
(Judge of the Court of Judicial Review, Tao Zhoufeng) Only when I think everything twice before doing it will I feel no regret.
(قاضي محكمة المراجعة القضائية ، Tao Zhoufeng) فقط عندما أفكر في كل شيء مرتين قبل القيام بذلك ، لن أشعر بأي ندم.
Mr. Tao.
السيد.  شخص.
You're not allowed to break into here.
لا يُسمح لك بالاقتحام هنا.
Don't do that.
لا تفعل ذلك.
There are no powders.
لا توجد مساحيق.
It's poisonless.
إنه غير سام.
Mr. Lan,
السيد.  لان ،
what's wrong?
ماالخطب؟
Mr. Tao,
السيد.  شخص،
I'm afraid a murderer
أخشى قاتل
wants to kill you.
يريد قتلك.
Please go to the Quietness Room to hide.
من فضلك اذهب إلى غرفة الهدوء للاختباء.
What should I do?
ماذا علي أن أفعل؟
I've been studying the methods
لقد كنت أدرس الأساليب
to educate and civilize criminals,
لتثقيف وتحضير المجرمين ،
so how could they
فكيف يمكنهم ذلك
kill me?
اقتلني؟
I thought
اعتقدت
no matter how bad criminals were,
بغض النظر عن مدى سوء المجرمين ،
they had consciences,
كان لديهم ضمائر ،
and as long as they watched
وطالما كانوا يشاهدون
cuckoos in spring,
الوقواق في الربيع ،
frosts and chrysanthemums in fall,
الصقيع والأقحوان في الخريف ،
and listened to rain and twitters,
واستمعت للمطر والتويتر ،
(Brochure of the Persuasion for Goodness) their souls would be purified, and they would repent.
(كتيب الإقناع للخير) سوف تتطهر أرواحهم ، وسوف يتوبون.
However,
لكن،
they're unworthy of my efforts.
إنهم لا يستحقون جهودي.
Mr. Tao,
السيد.  شخص،
the murderer who wants to kill you
القاتل الذي يريد قتلك
killed Chu Qi'er and Mr. Sun.
قتل Chu Qi'er والسيد Sun.
Why does he
لماذا يفعل
want to kill me?
تريد قتلي؟
It's a long story.
انها قصة طويلة.
The murderer's trick is unpredictable,
حيلة القاتل لا يمكن التنبؤ بها ،
and he could poison you without catching any attention.
ويمكنه أن يسممك دون أن يلفت انتباهك.
You'd better hide in the Quietness Room.
من الأفضل أن تختبئ في غرفة الهدوء.
The other flowers are also poisonless.
الزهور الأخرى هي أيضا غير سامة.
Peizhi.
Peizhi.
Miss Wu died.
ماتت الآنسة وو.
How could there be
كيف يمكن أن يكون هناك
a babarian in our civilized dynasty?
باباري في سلالتنا المتحضرة؟
Mr. Tao,
السيد.  شخص،
it's not time to say these words now.
لم يحن الوقت لقول هذه الكلمات الآن.
The defense in the Court of Judicial Review...
الدفاع في محكمة المراجعة القضائية ...
Mr. Wang,
السيد وانج،
just help yourself since you're here.
فقط ساعد نفسك بما أنك هنا.
You can set up the defense wherever you want.
يمكنك إعداد الدفاع أينما تريد.
Catch the criminal above all others.
قبض على المجرم فوق كل الآخرين.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Are you going to kill me?
هل ستقتلني؟
Mr. Ma?
السيد.  في؟
Mr. Ma,
السيد.  أماه
why do you come to me?
لماذا تاتي الي
Help me to read a letter.
ساعدني في قراءة الرسالة.
My son
ابني
is garrisoning the southern border,
يحمي الحدود الجنوبية ،
and I don't know other literate people,
ولا أعرف أشخاصًا آخرين متعلمين ،
so I come to you.
لذلك جئت اليك.
Okay.
تمام.
Father,
أب،
this letter is from your son, Ziyi.
هذه الرسالة من ابنك زيي.
How are you?
كيف حالكم؟
I live well in the army,
أنا أعيش جيدًا في الجيش ،
so you don't need to send money to me.
لذلك لا تحتاج إلى إرسال الأموال إلي.
Summer is coming,
الصيف قادم،
so please check the price of the silk,
لذا يرجى التحقق من سعر الحرير ،
and ask the tailor to make new clothes
واطلب من الخياط صنع ملابس جديدة
to spend summer.
لقضاء الصيف.
Even if you spend festivals alone,
حتى لو كنت تقضي المهرجانات وحدك
you can't spend them carelessly.
لا يمكنك إنفاقها بلا مبالاة.
You must eat glutinous rice of five colors
يجب أن تأكل أرزًا دبقًا من خمسة ألوان
to pray for good lucks.
للصلاة من أجل الحظ السعيد.
In the army,
في الجيش،
I'm looking forward to going home every day,
أتطلع إلى العودة إلى المنزل كل يوم ،
by Ziyi.
بواسطة Ziyi.
He's grown up.
لقد كبر.
My son has grown up.
لقد كبر ابني.
If you receive letters in the future,
إذا تلقيت رسائل في المستقبل ،
you can come to me directly.
يمكنك أن تأتي إليّ مباشرة.
I'll read them for you.
سأقرأها لك.
I won't bother you.
لن ازعجك.
I heard
سمعت
you and Mr. Wang from the Ministry of Justice
أنت والسيد وانغ من وزارة العدل
are investigating Miss Chu's case.
يحققون في قضية الآنسة تشو.
Yes.
نعم.
Unfortunately,
للأسف،
we haven't caught the murderer yet.
لم نقبض على القاتل بعد.
I suddenly remember
أتذكر فجأة
the way of Miss Chu's death
طريق موت الآنسة تشو
is like a southern legend
مثل أسطورة جنوبية
that Ziyi told me.
التي قالها لي زيي.
Please tell me that.
من فضلك قل لي ذلك.
In a mysterious place
في مكان غامض
in southern area,
في المنطقة الجنوبية ،
there was a mysterious clan.
كانت هناك عشيرة غامضة.
This clan
هذه العشيرة
was isolated
تم عزله
and lived
وعاش
in deep forests over the years.
في الغابات العميقة على مر السنين.
They had a skill,
كانت لديهم مهارة ،
which was
الذي كان
to deprive people's souls.
لحرمان نفوس الناس.
Because of that,
بسبب ذلك ،
they broke the taboo
كسروا المحرمات
and suffered the divine retribution in one night.
وعانى القصاص الإلهي في ليلة واحدة.
It's said that night,
قيل في تلك الليلة ،
the sky became as bright as the daytime in an instant
أصبحت السماء مشرقة مثل النهار في لحظة
after rumbling.
بعد الهادر.
Above the village,
فوق القرية
a cloud of scarlet mist
سحابة من الضباب القرمزي
was enveloping the sky and moon.
كان يلف السماء والقمر.
All clansmen
كل رجال العشائر
stood to the spot and died stiffly,
وقفت على الفور وماتت بصلابة ،
and their bodies
وأجسادهم
were cracked
متصدع
as if their souls had been deprived.
وكأن أرواحهم قد حرمت.
All big and important cases from every county
جميع القضايا الكبيرة والمهمة من كل مقاطعة
will be sent to the Court of Judicial Review to be reviewed again.
إلى محكمة المراجعة القضائية للمراجعة مرة أخرى.
If it's true,
إذا كان هذا صحيحا،
(The fourth year of Qingfeng) its recording scroll can be found
(السنة الرابعة من Qingfeng) يمكن العثور على لفائف التسجيل الخاصة بها
in the case archive in the Court of Judicial Review.
في أرشيف القضية في محكمة المراجعة القضائية.
(The first year of Yongxuan) Twenty years ago,
(السنة الأولى من Yongxuan) قبل عشرين عامًا ،
our emperor ascended the throne
صعد إمبراطورنا العرش
and changed the era name to be Yongxuan.
وغيرت اسم العصر ليكون Yongxuan.
(Wu Village)
(قرية وو)
(Moluo Village, Yueshang County, Lingnan District)
(قرية Moluo ، مقاطعة Yueshang ، مقاطعة Lingnan)
Scroll of Moluo Village, Yueshang County, Lingnan District.
التمرير لقرية Moluo ، مقاطعة Yueshang ، مقاطعة Lingnan.
That's it.
هذا كل شيء.
(Moluo Village, Yueshang County, Lingnan District)
(قرية Moluo ، مقاطعة Yueshang ، مقاطعة Lingnan)
In the first July of Yongxuan,
في أول يوليو من Yongxuan ،
a homicide case
قضية قتل
happened in Moluo Village, Lingnan District.
حدث في قرية Moluo ، مقاطعة Lingnan.
No villagers survived.
لم ينج أي قرويين.
All of them were stiffened and died.
كلهم ماتوا وتيبسوا.
At that time, a cloud of scarlet mist
في ذلك الوقت ، كانت سحابة من الضباب القرمزي
enveloping the sky and moon.
يلف السماء والقمر.
Because of the flash flood,
بسبب الفيضانات المفاجئة ،
the gallery road was destroyed.
تم تدمير طريق المعرض.
It cost several months to fix it.
تكلف عدة أشهر لإصلاحه.
It was found the villagers had practiced the sorcery
وجد أن القرويين كانوا يمارسون السحر
and suffered the divine retribution in the scarlet mist.
وعانى الانتقام الالهي في الضباب القرمزي.
There were no objections after the review.
لم تكن هناك اعتراضات بعد المراجعة.
The case was ended.
تم إنهاء القضية.
There are no divine retributions in the world.
لا توجد جزاءات إلهية في العالم.
It seems
يبدو
people in the Moluo Village were also killed by the red poison.
أشخاص في قرية مولو قتلوا بالسم الأحمر.
How long did it take from Capital City to Moluo Village at that time?
كم من الوقت استغرقت من العاصمة إلى قرية مولو في ذلك الوقت؟
Go back now.
ارجع الآن.
Where are you going?
إلى أين تذهب؟
It's none of your business.
هذا ليس من شأنك.
Do you find clues?
هل تجد أدلة؟
Maybe I can help you.
ربما يمكنني مساعدتك.
Don't you want to know how long it took
لا تريد أن تعرف كم من الوقت استغرق
from Capital City to Moluo Village?
من العاصمة إلى قرية مولو؟
The terrain was complex there,
كانت التضاريس معقدة هناك ،
so the moving speed was different.
لذلك كانت سرعة الحركة مختلفة.
It's hard to calculate it specifically.
من الصعب حسابها على وجه التحديد.
but I can help you.
لكن يمكنني مساعدتك.
You had to spend five days
كان عليك قضاء خمسة أيام
to cross the lakes by boat
لعبور البحيرات بالقوارب
and spend seven days
وقضاء سبعة أيام
to pass the forests.
لتمرير الغابات.
It was hard to pass the marshes,
كان من الصعب عبور الأهوار ،
so you had to spend twenty days.
لذلك كان عليك قضاء عشرين يومًا.
If the map is correct,
إذا كانت الخريطة صحيحة ،
it cost about ninety days,
تكلف حوالي تسعين يومًا ،
(Moluo Village) which was one month longer
(قرية مولو) والتي كانت أطول بشهر واحد
than going on the official road.
من السير على الطريق الرسمي.
Zhang Ping,
تشانغ بينغ ،
go back now.
ارجع الآن.
I have something to talk with Peizhi.
لدي شيء لأتحدث إليه مع Peizhi.
I should know
يجب أن أعرف
everything that is related to this case.
كل ما يتعلق بهذه القضية.
It's none of your business.
هذا ليس من شأنك.
Why?
لماذا ا؟
If the two cases are related,
إذا كانت الحالتان مرتبطتان ،
it could help to catch the criminal
يمكن أن يساعد في القبض على المجرم
if we find out the truth.
إذا اكتشفنا الحقيقة.
Zhang Ping,
تشانغ بينغ ،
this is my private thing.
هذا هو الشيء الخاص بي.
Don't you worry about Mr. Tao?
ألا تقلق بشأن السيد تاو؟
No one is guarding the Court of Judicial Review,
لا أحد يحرس محكمة المراجعة القضائية ،
so go back to check it now.
لذا ارجع للتحقق من ذلك الآن.
No.
رقم.
Send off the guest.
طرد الضيف.
Moluo Village
قرية مولو
was on the post road.
كان على طريق البريد.
My father left home in early April in the first year of Yongxuan.
غادر والدي المنزل في أوائل أبريل في السنة الأولى من Yongxuan.
He encountered the flash flood on the way,
واجه الفيضان السريع في الطريق ،
and the gallery road was destroyed.
ودُمر طريق المعرض.
He sent a letter to me,
أرسل لي رسالة ،
saying he had to make a detour
قائلا إنه كان عليه أن يقوم بالالتفاف
and walked three months to arrive in the southern area.
وسار ثلاثة أشهر للوصول إلى المنطقة الجنوبية.
After three months,
بعد ثلاثة اشهر
it was early in July.
كان ذلك في أوائل شهر يوليو.
Didn't the village suffer the divine retribution at that time?
ألم تعاني القرية من القصاص الإلهي في ذلك الوقت؟
He was condemned when returning to Capital City early in October.
وقد أدين عند عودته إلى العاصمة في أوائل أكتوبر.
After calculating the time,
بعد حساب الوقت ،
I found he started the return journey near the village.
وجدت أنه بدأ رحلة العودة بالقرب من القرية.
He spent three months back,
أمضى ثلاثة أشهر إلى الوراء ،
and the time matched.
والوقت المتطابق.
That's right.
صحيح.
Peizhi,
Peizhi ،
don't you think the two things
ألا تعتقد الأمرين
are very coincident?
متزامنة جدا؟
As soon as your father came there,
حالما جاء والدك هناك ،
the village was perished.
هلكت القرية.
It was indeed strange
لقد كان غريبًا حقًا
back then.
في ذلك الوقت.
As I recall my father's words before his leaving,
كما أتذكر كلمات والدي قبل مغادرته ،
I always feel he wouldn't do bad things
أشعر دائمًا أنه لن يفعل أشياء سيئة
although the trip to the southern area was dangerous.
على الرغم من أن الرحلة إلى المنطقة الجنوبية كانت محفوفة بالمخاطر.
I'm going to
انا ذاهب الى
the southern area.
المنطقة الجنوبية.
If it's smooth,
إذا كان الأمر سلسًا ،
I'll spend about two months.
سأقضي حوالي شهرين.
If not,
ان لم،
I'm afraid I have to spend more time.
أخشى أن أقضي المزيد من الوقت.
If it's not smooth,
إذا لم يكن الأمر سلسًا ،
will you encounter dangers?
هل ستواجه مخاطر؟
Could you
يمكنك
cancel the trip?
إلغاء الرحلة؟
Zengzi once said to Zixiang,
قال Zengzi مرة ل Zixiang ،
"Are you brave?
"هل انت شجاع؟
I heard
سمعت
the real braveness from Confucius."
الشجاعة الحقيقية من كونفوشيوس ".
Then
ثم
what is the real braveness
ما هي الشجاعة الحقيقية
in Confucius' words?
بكلمات كونفوشيوس؟
He said thousands of people stopped me,
قال إن آلاف الأشخاص أوقفوني ،
but I would still go,
لكن ما زلت سأذهب ،
so I'm not afraid.
لذلك أنا لست خائفا.
I just don't want others
أنا فقط لا أريد الآخرين
to take this risk
لاتخاذ هذا الخطر
for me.
لي.
Father,
أب،
keep this sachet.
احتفظ بهذا الكيس.
Regard it
فيما يتعلق به
as my accompany to you.
كمرافقتك لك.
When I met my father again,
عندما قابلت والدي مرة أخرى ،
he was on the guillotine.
كان على المقصلة.
Although everyone said he was a traitor,
على الرغم من أن الجميع قال إنه كان خائنًا ،
I know
أنا أعرف
he wouldn't betray the country
لن يخون البلد
even if he was threatened to be killed.
حتى لو هدد بالقتل.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
If the criminal of this case
إذا كان المجرم في هذه القضية
is related to the Moluo Village's case,
مرتبط بقضية قرية مولو ،
we may find out the truth
قد نكتشف الحقيقة
of my father's wrong death
وفاة والدي بالخطأ
if we catch him.
إذا أمسكنا به.
Then why don't you tell this to Zhang Ping?
إذن لماذا لا تخبر تشانغ بينغ بهذا؟
He is organized
إنه منظم
and knows the Water Illusion,
ويعرف وهم الماء ،
so perhaps he can help you.
لذلك ربما يمكنه مساعدتك.
The Army for Southward Crusade were defeated,
هزم جيش الحملة الصليبية الجنوبية ،
and thousands of people died in the war.
ومات الآلاف من الناس في الحرب.
The court didn't want to mention it.
لم ترغب المحكمة في ذكر ذلك.
My father admitted betraying the country,
اعترف والدي بخيانته للوطن ،
but the court didn't investigate
لكن المحكمة لم تحقق
the strangeness inside it
الغرابة بداخله
and tried to end the case as soon as possible.
وحاول إنهاء القضية في أسرع وقت ممكن.
Since they hid it hard,
منذ أن أخفوا الأمر بشدة ،
there must be something behind it.
يجب أن يكون هناك شيء خلفه.
If we investigate the case again,
إذا حققنا في القضية مرة أخرى ،
it means we'll challenge the authority of the court.
هذا يعني أننا سنطعن في سلطة المحكمة.
If Zhang Ping, who is reckless, knows that,
إذا كان تشانغ بينغ ، المتهور ، يعرف ذلك ،
he will cause bigger trouble
سوف يسبب مشكلة أكبر
within two days.
في غضون يومين.
Sir.
سيد.
Why does he spend so long in the bathroom?
لماذا يقضي كل هذا الوقت في الحمام؟
Are you okay?
هل انت بخير؟
How about I enter to check you?
ماذا عن الدخول للتحقق منك؟
I might have eaten something that caused a diarrhea.
ربما أكلت شيئًا تسبب في حدوث إسهال.
Zhang Ping is straightforward
Zhang Ping واضح ومباشر
and has experienced nothing in officialdom.
ولم يختبر شيئًا في السلطة الرسمية.
That's why he could insist to his conscience.
لهذا السبب يمكنه الإصرار على ضميره.
This is
هذا هو
very priceless.
لا تقدر بثمن جدا.
But because of that,
لكن بسبب ذلك ،
he doesn't know how dark the officialdom is
لا يعرف كم هي مظلمة السلطة الرسمية
and always has a breach
ودائمًا ما يكون لديه خرق
of propriety when doing things.
اللياقة عند القيام بالأشياء.
I'm worried that he will fail from his strong toughness.
أنا قلق من أنه سيفشل من قوته القوية.
Peizhi,
Peizhi ،
leave this matter to me.
اترك هذا الأمر لي.
I'll find out the truth of your father's
سأكتشف حقيقة والدك
wrong death at all costs.
الموت الخطأ بأي ثمن.
We've been guarding the Court of Judicial Review for so long,
لقد كنا نحرس محكمة المراجعة القضائية لفترة طويلة ،
but why hasn't the murderer acted yet?
لكن لماذا لم يتصرف القاتل بعد؟
You've been guarding for a night,
لقد كنت تحرس لمدة ليلة ،
so go back to rest early.
لذا عد للراحة مبكرًا.
No one is in the street
لا أحد في الشارع
since it's early in the morning.
منذ الصباح الباكر.
What is he doing?
ماذا يفعل؟
(Court of Judicial Review)
(محكمة المراجعة القضائية)
I've investigated overnight
لقد حققت بين عشية وضحاها
and found the corpses of Mr. Sun and Chu Qi'er
وعثروا على جثتي السيد صن وتشو كيير
were stolen
لقد سرقت
besides Miss Wu's and the four gentlemen' from the Feng family.
إلى جانب الآنسة وو والأربعة السادة من عائلة فنغ.
The hole under the secret canal also collapsed.
كما انهارت الحفرة تحت القناة السرية.
How about you?
ماذا عنك؟
Sir,
سيد،
we were divided into three teams to guard.
تم تقسيمنا إلى ثلاث فرق للحراسة.
Two teams would guard by turns every hour,
فريقان يحرسان بالتناوب كل ساعة ،
and the rest team would keep searching the Court of Judicial Review.
وسيواصل الفريق الآخر البحث في محكمة المراجعة القضائية.
We didn't find the Scarlet Mist Spray.
لم نجد بخاخ سكارليت ميست.
Mr. Tao went to bathroom twice
ذهب السيد تاو إلى الحمام مرتين
and ate night snacks twice.
وأكلت وجبات خفيفة ليلية مرتين.
No other extraordinary things happened.
لم تحدث أشياء أخرى غير عادية.
Don't slack off, and continue to guard heavily.
لا تتهاون ، واستمر في الحراسة بشدة.
- Yes.
- نعم.  - نعم.
Although there are no clues,
على الرغم من عدم وجود أدلة ،
I'm afraid it's not a long-term solution
أخشى أنه ليس حلاً طويل الأمد
for us to stay in the Court of Judicial Review
بالنسبة لنا للبقاء في محكمة المراجعة القضائية
and wait for the murderer.
وانتظر القاتل.
Sir,
سيد،
when I and Zhang Ping finished guarding and left,
عندما انتهيت أنا وزانغ بينغ من الحراسة وغادرا ،
we met a dumb embalmer on the way.
التقينا محنط غبي في الطريق.
He was pulling a flatbed cart of corpses
كان يسحب عربة من الجثث
and signed he was unable to pull it.
ووقع أنه غير قادر على سحبه.
He didn't stop pestering us
لم يتوقف عن مضايقتنا
and wanted us to help him.
وأراد منا مساعدته.
He looked weird,
بدا غريبًا ،
and so was the way Zhang Ping looked at him.
وهكذا كانت الطريقة التي نظر إليه تشانغ بينغ.
Then
ثم
Zhang Ping went to help him.
ذهب تشانغ بينغ لمساعدته.
I also wanted to help Zhang Ping,
أردت أيضًا مساعدة Zhang Ping ،
but he teased me.
لكنه سخر مني.
Even pepper made you feel pungent,
حتى الفلفل جعلك تشعر بالنفاذة
not to mention smelly corpses.
ناهيك عن الجثث ذات الرائحة الكريهة.
What did he mean?
ماذا كان يعني؟
Who was disgusted at pepper?
من كان مقرف من الفلفل؟
What else did he say?
ماذا قال أيضا؟
Won't Mr. Lan come later?
ألن يأتي السيد لان لاحقًا؟
Just wait for him
فقط انتظره
here.
هنا.
He also said other words.
كما قال كلمات أخرى.
My home is in the same direction,
بيتي في نفس الاتجاه ،
but the Lan's Mansion isn't.
لكن قصر لان ليس كذلك.
No.
رقم.
Zhang Ping's home is in Xiaohaozi Lane,
يقع منزل Zhang Ping في Xiaohaozi Lane ،
so he must go in the southeast direction.
لذلك يجب أن يذهب في الاتجاه الجنوبي الشرقي.
But the Cemetery is in the west direction,
لكن المقبرة باتجاه الغرب
so how could his home be in the same direction?
فكيف يكون بيته في نفس الاتجاه؟
It must be a hint.
يجب أن يكون تلميحًا.
Xuexiao,
Xuexiao ،
keep one team here to guard.
احتفظ بفريق واحد هنا للحراسة.
Others, follow me to the Cemetery.
آخرون ، اتبعوني إلى المقبرة.
Yes.
نعم.
=A League of Nobleman=
= عصبة النبلاء =